The next stage of creating our game is something
次のセクションでは、ゲーム開発の
that's good to address early on.
早い段階で対応すると良い、
What tags do we need for our game
ゲームに必要なタグの検討と
and how are we going to manage them?
それらをどのように管理するか、について取り上げます。
Unity projects start out with some tags
Unity プロジェクトは同梱されてるタグがありますが、
already made. But we are going to need
今回はカスタムで
a few more for our game. One of the most
もう幾つか足すことにします。
common uses of tags it to find references to
最も一般的なタグの使用方法は
game objects or their components.
ゲームオブジェクトまたはコンポーネントへの参照を見つけることです。
When thinking about tags that you need
必要なタグについて考えるとき、
it's often best to consider which scripts
他のものを参照する内容を
will need to reference others. For example,
特定すると便利です。
our game is going to have a game controller,
例えば今回のゲームでは幾つかのスクリプトのついた
with some scripts on.
ゲームコントローラが必要です。
Lots of other scripts in the game will
ゲームの中の多くのスクリプトは
need a reference to those scripts, so we will
これらのスクリプトに対して参照を行うので
need a game controller tag.
ゲームコントローラ タグは必要、ということです。
This is one of the tags already provided by
これは Unity にデフォルトで同梱されてますが、
Unity. There are 5 tags we will need,
今回は同梱されてないタグを 5 つ新規で
which aren't there by default.
必要となります。
AlarmLight, Siren, DirectionalLight,
AlarmLight, Siren, DirectionalLight,
Fader and Enemy.
Fader および Enemy です。
These have already been added to your project.
今回はプロジェクトにあらかじめ追加してあります。
When you reference tags in code
コードの中でタグを参照するとき
they're written as strings and
文字列として書かれ、
are not auto completed.
また自動補完はされません。
In order to minimise error we are going to
ミスを避けるため、
create a short script to store all of
全てのタグの文字列を含む短いコードを
the tag strings so that we can reference
用意します。
them as variables instead.
これにより変数として参照出来るので便利です。
For convenience we will call this script
このスクリプトはシンプルに
simply Tags.
Tags という名前をつけます。
Select the Scripts folder in the project panel
プロジェクト パネルの Scripts フォルダを選択して
and go to Create and choose C# Script.
Create をクリックして C# Script を選択します。
Name the script Tags.
スクリプトの名前を Tags にします。
Double click the icon to open for editing.
アイコンをダブルクリックして編集します。
Again we are going to remove the default function
ここでも Unity があらかじめ用意した関数は
that Unity gives us.
削除します。
This script in fact won't use any functions.
このスクリプトは関数を一切使用しません。
For each of the tags we are going to store
各々のタグについて、
a public constant string variable.
パブリックな constant 文字列を変数として格納します。
Here we are using the keyword const.
ここでは const というキーワードを使用します。
Const means that the variable it is applied to
const の意味は
cannot be changed, and instead
値が変更出来ないということなので、
becomes known as a constant.
いわゆる定数として知られてます。
Since the data cannot be changed it is the
全てのクラスのインスタンスにおいて
same for every instance of the class
固定の値です。
and so it is available through the class
そしてクラスのインスタンスを通してではなく
instead of through an instance of that class.
クラスを通して利用可能となります。
This works in a similar way to using
これは Mathf のような static 関数を使用する
static functions like the Mathf functions.
ときと同じような形で活用できるという意味です。
To call, for example, Lerp for floats
例えば float に対して Lerp をコールするとき
we use the class name Mathf followed by .lerp.
クラス名である Mathf の後に Lerp を記述します。
If we wanted to reference one of the strings
今回の場合は、格納する文字列を参照するときは
that we store here we simply need to
Tags. と入力して
type Tags. followed by the name of the constant.
定数の名前を続けて入力します。
For example, Tags.player.
例えば Tags.Player とします。
To complete the script we are going to need
スクリプトを完成するには
a few more constants. As previously
前述のとおり、定数がもう幾つか必要です。
stated we need to reference the alarm light
アラーム ライトへの参照が必要であり、
and we have given it the alarmLight tag.
AlarmLights というタグを作ったので
So we will make a constant for that.
そのための定数を作成します。
We have also seen that we will be using the
また前述のとおり、さらにアラーム音を発するタワーにも
Siren tag to reference the towers that
Siren タグを使用します。
play the alarm sound. So we will make a
また、このための定数を
constant for that.
作成します。
The game controller will be where we store
ゲームコントローラには、
the last known location of the player
敵キャラが追跡する際に把握している
when the enemies are chasing him.
プレイヤーの最新の位置を格納します。
As such they will need a reference to the game controller.
このためゲームコントローラへの参照が必要です。
A tag already exists so we just need
すでにタグは存在するので
to make the constant.
定数を作成することだけ必要です。
When the alarm light turns on we want
アラームライトがオンになったとき、
to dim the main light. As such we are going
メインライトを暗くすることが目的です。
to need a constant for that too.
このため、そのための定数も準備します。
When the scene starts and ends
シーン開始、終了時に
we want to fade to and from black.
黒色との間をフェードイン、アウトさせたいとします。
To do this we are going to use a GUI texture
このためにGUIテクスチャ を使用します。
and we will need to reference the script on it.
さらに、これにアタッチしたスクリプトへの参照が必要です。
Let's add a constant for the fader.
フェード（Fader） に定数を追加します。
A final tag that we need is for a less obvious reason.
必要となる最後のタグはシンプルな目的です。
Our game is going to have sliding doors
ゲームには、プレイヤーが近づいたときにスライドして開くドアを
which will open when the player goes near them.
用意しています。
However they should also open for enemies
しかしこれらは敵の場合も開く必要があるため、
so we need a tag to identify our enemies.
敵を識別するタグもまた必要になります。
Now that this is complete, save the script
これを完成した後は、スクリプトを保存したうえで
and return to the editor.
エディタに戻ります。
At this point we will tidy up our scripts.
この時点で全てのスクリプトを整理していくことにします。
In the Assets folder you will find the
Assets フォルダには作成済みの
alarm light that we made using the
アラートライトがあり、これらは
Add Component button. When using the this
Add Component ボタンにより作成していました。
button scripts are created in the
このボタンを使用するとき、スクリプトは Assets フォルダの直下に作成されます。
root of assets.
このタイミングで Scripts フォルダに
So simply drag and drop it in to the scripts folder
ドラッグ＆ドロップすることで
to tidy up, and remember to do that
簡単に整理することにして、
whenever you use the Add Component button
今後も Add Component を使用するとき、この作業を
in this way.
行うようにして下さい。
Now, go to File - Save Scene
メニューから File - Save Scene を選択して、
and File - Save Project.
さらに File - Save Project を選択します。
In the next assignment we will create the
次のセクションでは
screen fader to fade in and out our level
シーン フェード（Fader）を作成してゲーム開始および終了時に
at the start and end of the game.
レベルをフェードイン、アウトするようにします。 (翻訳:gamesonytablet)